Karan: Exactly.
Exactly.
Alright, looks like,
like we're recording now.
Okay.
So let's mark a morning conversation.
It's, it's, it's a total
180 degrees from that.
Uh, the, the important part really is, uh,
that we have a pretty incredible solution.
That should not just be confined to
one customer or should not be just
confined to our traditional, you
know, professional services mindset.
Right.
Uh, it's, it's something that needs
to grow, something that we can
actually benefit a lot of customers.
And also something that I, I, again,
based on what I've heard from you
guys is there's a, there's a lot of
interest that the ecosystem is showing.
In terms of what, what this
could potentially look like.
So, so of course we'll talk more about it
next week and, uh, in San Francisco Cric.
Um, but I think the, the starting
point we just need to kind of
understand and think about is,
okay, we build something incredible.
We've, we've solved a very
hard engineering problem.
Um.
In the end, there will always be the hard
engineering problem to solve for, but
how can we take components of this and
start to really showcase ourselves as
experts in, in kind of the drone based
AI full stack, if you will.
I don't know how else to
kind of characterize it.
AI is one portion of it.
It's, it's actually the full stack of it
that's, that's also very, very powerful.
That connects the entire.
Pipeline from the moment you capture
the pictures, images on the drone
and actually make it visible as an
actionable insight to the end user.
So, so something for us to just
think about before, before we do
that I would, you know, I have, of
course, I heard snippets of ecosystem
conversation from, from you honors and
Cedric, both Genack and Sky Ladder.
I would like to just.
Get into little more details on that
as well, in terms of what they've said,
what they've liked, what they've not
liked, whatever the conversations are,
how can we get involved with them before
we kind of start to put some, some,
some level of detail or action items in
our, in what we need to do to go from
just being the best kept secret at GATX.
Uh, to something that we can
showcase and share and deliver for,
you know, a lot more organizations
across, across the world.
Does that sound like a good plan?
Do you wanna talk about, or do you have
anything else on your mind that you wanna
talk about in this, in this context?
No,
Cedric: I think that's,
that's a good place to start.
I, well, I guess the other piece
too, like as far as demand,
there's like statements of.
Gaps in the market.
But I also think it would be helpful
to kind of summarize what is the
solution that we're building for
GATX if we were to define that
as like a series of capabilities.
Then we can sort of extract
a use case out of it as well.
Yes.
Like we talked before about vision, ai,
drones, piloting, visualization, all that.
Karan: Yeah.
And then, then of course, piecing
together the components of saying,
okay, which ones, which ones we have
gotten really good at, which can be
caught productized, and which ones will
actually end up being, you know, the
layering of professional services on top.
Because every, every
solution will be different.
Yet we'll have the same components.
Right.
So, so let's park.
That hopefully we, we'll touch
on that later in this call.
But s can you just give some thoughts on
what your conversation with Genack and
Skyla and others has been like, or, or
Cedric and, and what has their feedback
been like and what are they interested
in when they look at A-G-A-T-X solution?
Anders: Yeah, I mean, um,
conversations we have are, are really
interesting 'cause we're trying to.
Initial conversations, we're
trying to explain this concept.
You know, it's, it's asset management.
We're using drones, we're using camera
drones to kind of, um, cover all the
outdoor areas and then, uh, injecting
that into a bespoke pipeline that
analyzes these images, stitches them
together, and then creates, you know,
a digital representative, um, of this
asset, uh, of, or of these assets.
And I think.
Just the concept of actually performing
all those different steps is interesting
people, because there's a lot of AI
out there, there's a lot of, you know,
hype and of all these individual steps.
So you see this very
attractive keynote on A POC.
Somebody's got working,
but it's very isolated.
So that one case.
Where what we've actually managed
to do is apply this AI to an, to an
actual industry, into a process that
exists already that we have improved.
So instead of just having this very
isolated case of, you know, doing
object detection on rail cars, which is
a keynote in and of itself, honestly,
mm-hmm.
Anders: We have taken it all the way from
the capture mechanism all the way through
the infrastructure that is required
to actually run a pipeline like this.
Translating it into data that is
presentable and actually in that
you can interact with as well
and feed back into the model.
So that entire journey is
just, seems unprecedented.
It seems like people are flying
drones and then they do something
with those photos, or they do, or
they start the other way around.
They haven't, uh, they have
the image pipeline and they're
trying to ingest images somehow.
But you know.
Drone one mechanism or static
cameras in a manufacturing
environment could be another.
Um, but we've actually managed to put
it all together and make that work.
So that case is just really,
really appealing to people.
Um,
Cedric: yeah, I think the other thing
that we have a unique capability
on is the full stack solution.
So like the ability to, like if I were
to like sort of abstract the use case,
it's um, identify a geographic area.
Capture images from the sky build, uh,
a model like build a model to be able
to either identify images based on IDs
or build some sort of landscape, um, of
where those objects exist, track them
over time, which is another piece of it.
And then visualize that information
for customers, which takes it,
you know, fully from end to end.
But ideally, we would
have a solution where.
You would just be able to deploy
this toolkit, customize the AI model.
Customize the visualization,
go from there.
Anders: Yeah.
The magic really happens in our
interpretation of the image data coming
in because we don't just show a photogram
graphic stitch of what we're capturing.
We actually interpret everything
we see on these image.
We correlate different images
of the same asset samples, and
then extract meaningful data.
Models for that to represent in
a, a application where everything
is, you know, outlined super neat.
So it's not geographically
accurate necessarily.
'cause it doesn't have to be, we're
actually presenting it in a context
that makes sense for that end user.
Cedric: There's a domain specificity to
Anders: it.
It's, it's quite elaborated.
I think that comes off very clear
without us having to say it.
So.
These companies are very interested
in, in is of course, well we, we
can provide all that hardware.
I mean, we can handle all this
hardware, we can handle, you know,
the edge components of all this.
But you as software providers actually
have experience in managing to make
this work, which is something that.
I feel like they haven't heard this from a
potential partner before, so that's Yeah.
Cedric: They have, they have people
that know how to operate drones.
Yeah.
Or like agriculture.
You know, there are, there are solutions
and companies out there that are building
on top of like desktop privates for
doing this, but there's, there's nothing.
It really starts at.
Drone expertise as opposed to
like custom software application
development expertise.
We're coming at it from a, from
different, different direction.
Yeah.
Patrick: Go ahead Patrick.
Oh, sorry.
Put the donuts on the screen.
I've been dying to put
the donuts on the screen.
I can't wait to create my own, my
own gen moji of myself and then have
myself floating through the screen.
Um, so guys, I think, um.
Uh, I think this is
really Karin, first of all, I'm super
happy we're having this discussion
because I think it's, it's important
that we spend time as we have in the
last couple of minutes getting to a
differentiated statement because there
are lots of companies out there who
will say, oh, we already use drones.
Um, so they'll say, oh, we use drones.
Uh, so like, we don't
need to talk to you guys.
And so we need to be.
Yes, but we need to have all our yes
buts, because I think what we're doing
is really unique and, um, this ability
to autonomously operate the drone
autonomously, interpret what the drone
is seeing, and then the conditions that
we're trying to assess using the drone
and that interpretation process, right.
So I'd like us to get to a
place where we talk about, um.
Yes, we, yes, we use a drone.
The drone can autonomously operate itself.
The drone will take photos, and those
photos will be autonomously interpreted by
a vision AI model that we're gonna develop
and the things that it's looking for.
I really like Cedric, you said
movement, so I, you know, okay.
Has this moved.
But then let's think about what
would be the three or four other
conditions would we'd be looking for?
You know, has, has there been a
change in the status of that asset
or the condition of that asset?
What are the types of things we would
look for under those conditions?
Um, I like the, and when Cedric, when
you and I talked about CN Rail way
back when, which I'm still trying to
get us into, and hopefully this week's
meeting will get us to start that
discussion, but like being able to say.
How do we classify these assets?
So I think we need to come with the
variety of lists of things that we do
using vision ai, and I think we also
need to be clear guys that we don't get.
Cut off at the knees at the pictures
and interpretation of pictures.
I think we need to say this creates a data
foundation that you didn't have before,
and what it allows you to do once you
have the data is these five things, right?
Like that is the next part that
we're gonna help eventually.
GATX to say, okay, I want to, I want to
reorient all the cars in the yard based
on the fact that I don't have any of
these parts available for the next six
months, and therefore I can't do that
maintenance anyway, so let's reorient it.
Or I have, I want to reorient all the
cars because Walmart has a whole bunch
of cars and they're really pissed
off at me, and so I'm gonna reorient
the cars to service that customer.
Like we need to come up
with those scenarios.
Because I think we have an incredible
story to go out to the market with
not just customers, but also drone
operators, and there's a pile of
them in Canada and in the US that do
agriculture and infrastructure and
oil and gas fields and whatever it is.
We have a hell of a story to tell if
we can just get ahead of the Yeah.
Buts.
We have
Anders: to kill the Yeah.
Buts early.
I very much agree, Patrick,
and in all honesty, I mean.
From here, this is when
it gets interesting.
When you have that data foundation,
that's when the business case
becomes very interesting.
It becomes That's right.
Tangible to all the operations people
who are trying to optimize, right?
Yeah.
But
Anders: up until now, what
we've done for GHX is a very
technically interesting project.
We have to, of course, we're addressing
executives who have to decide on yeah,
why they would implement this, and all
the planning and scheduling that we have
enabled now that we've got this data five.
Karan: So if, if we have to, if we have
to frame the layers here, guys, um,
I see the layers as follows, right?
Let's just think about this entire stack
and we'll, it'll become more abstracted
as we go up because the business problem
becomes different for different customer.
We have the hardware layer or the stack,
right, which is of course, we know how
to operate drones, manage drones, and
all those pieces that less of a scale
or less of a ip, but more of a scale.
Then we have the capture layer.
Right, which is we know how to fly
missions, we know what to capture, we
know where to capture what exactly those,
the, the, the actual act of capturing
those photos, that, that makes sense
for that particular business problem.
The third layer is, is geographical,
uh, understanding, right?
So, so the lifelong coordinates, because
no matter what the problem might be.
If it's strains or if it's if it's
utility poles, or if it's agriculture,
you always need to be aware of
what you're looking at, right?
So geographical positioning will be
critical no matter what the solution is.
Am I?
Am I okay so far?
Cedric: Yeah.
Karan: Okay.
So these, these are the
three layers, right?
And then, and at the, on the top
of this, on this layer, on top of
this layer is the object detection.
So I know where I am now.
I'm detecting what I'm
looking at right now.
Now, object detection of course, will
be different in different scenarios, but
I'm hoping there is enough IP that we
built out that we can say this, we, we,
we have object detection capabilities.
That are stronger than what you
would ever find, you know, out of
the box from any of the players.
Uh, of course I'm, I'm probably making
this up and, but let's just call,
there is an object detection layer,
which is part ip, part professional
services or part, kind of, you know,
custom work that needs to be done.
And on the top, object detection
is really, you have, uh, a visual
representation of that particular
information, whether it's a, it's a
heat map for an agricultural company
or it's, it's a, it's a location for
a. Or a manufacturing location or a
maintenance location, or it's, you know,
what exactly are the utility poles in
what direction and where, where exactly
they are, what connecting to who,
you know, or, or any of those pieces.
And then at the very top, you have the
real business value of, okay, now what?
Now you are integration
into your existing systems.
You have data representation
that's richer.
And then you have, on top of that, you
have additional intelligence and analytics
like planning and scheduling, right?
For example.
Uh, or it could be work order execution
or work order notification, right?
You could actually create work
order coming out of drones.
Um, so am I, am I 80% okay in this, uh,
uh, correct in this particular stack?
Anders: I mean there you could
elaborate on some of these steps.
For example, funneling OCR and
object detection and all that.
But, but I mean, this is, the general
concept is correct and it will be
very custom, very bespoke once you
get towards the top because you,
you try to hit a specific business
Cedric: there, a couple.
I agree, like you can object detection
kind of falls into object classification,
object identification, the whole shebang.
Yeah.
Cedric: Yeah.
There's, and then I would say the other
thing to consider is the, the medium.
So right now we've been focused on
basically capturing static images, but
there's a different sort of intelligence
that you could do if you were flying
continuously and identifying objects
while the drone is in the field.
Mm-hmm.
Um, so.
I think there's a lot of legs there.
And then the planning and optimization
and enterprise integration, um, would
be kind of the unique capabilities
that we would have as well.
Uh, so yeah, to echo that, um, what,
what you and Patrick were saying.
I, I agree.
Patrick: Okay.
So you have a, you have a, you have a
hardware, you have a capture, you have
a, a deciphering location, location.
Well, the deciphering is
location, identification,
classification, and condition.
Karan: No, no, those are the two.
Two, they're two separate parts.
Right.
There's, in my view, there is a location.
You have location aware, and
then you have Object Aware.
Cedric: Yeah.
And it is, it is effectively a
down, like we could do all sorts
of analysis, but I think the narrow
is figuring out what's where.
And when, right.
So like what were, when, what
is identification analysis?
Uh, I would just layer all that as like
stuff that happens after the drone flies
or while the drone is flying analysis.
No, I actually
Anders: agree with Koran because by, by.
Separating it.
You are separating what we already
know and what is very deterministic
off of the information you get.
And then the interpretation part
because object detection is you
are interested in these specific
things, let's identify those.
And that's what we train the model for.
That's the AI part because actually,
Karan: because the one, in my opinion,
what's there is very AI specific, right?
It's object detection, classification,
segmentation, all those pieces.
And where is it?
Is more.
Super imposition of that AI
information on the location itself.
Sorry, go ahead.
You were saying something.
Cedric: Well, I was, I was gonna
say, it might be an interesting
exercise to map this onto an OODA
loop, if you're familiar with that.
Um, like, observe,
orient, decide, and act.
Mm-hmm.
So like the side would be.
All the stuff that happens after
we've oriented on the information.
And then act is also kind of an
interesting thing too, because being
able to track what people are doing
with this information, um, would,
would be, and the feedback loop.
And the feedback loop.
So that's the idea with the noodle loop
is it's basically, it is a loop, right?
So every single drone run,
every single analysis.
You're doing something with that
information that is then feeding into the
next thing that you observe and orient.
The other piece of this, and I think
this is a unique tri for capability,
is I wouldn't necessarily discount
our ability to visualize stuff.
So there are tools, for example, that
can generate what we call ortho map, just
like a higher resolution Google map that's
constructed from what the drone just saw.
Um, but as we demonstrated with our
expertise in spatial, there's a lot
that we can do with the information
that we capture and the mode in which
it's, you know, it's, it's viewed.
I, I still think it would be a dream
scenario if we could build out 3D
model of what the drone just saw and
pop it into a vision pro that itself.
Is a compelling, um, offering.
Yeah.
And
Cedric: one that I think Tri Fork Us,
or Tri Fork in general is uniquely
positioned to provide and it has legs
with partnerships not only with, you know,
GenPath and Skylander, but I think most
importantly like Apple and DJI and Stadio
and all the drone vendors, they don't
have any solution like this right now.
Um.
I think if DJI can stay in the mix from a
regulatory standpoint, I think that also
has international implications as well.
Karan: Yeah, exactly.
Um, hey Karen,
Patrick: can I add one thing there?
Yes sir. Where does the timing go?
I would think that the location awareness
should be location plus timing, awareness.
Okay.
Cedric: Yeah.
Yeah.
Location time.
Patrick: Then your object awareness.
I had like select selection and
identification, which is being able to
select what it's gonna take photos of.
Yeah.
Identifying what they are, then
classifying them and then tracking
some measure of condition.
Cedric: Yeah.
And, and effectively like object
awareness also feeds into location
and timing awareness because
there will be cases where.
There is an OCR, there isn't a way to
identify an object just through vision
AI alone, but you could have users,
let's, let's say in the case of GATX,
there are new car marks to read, but
they happen to know, okay, this car with
this rest pattern is GATX 1, 2, 3, 4.
From that input, we could then
re-identify that same object, you
know, through object awareness.
Um, and so there is sort of
the feedback loop between.
Stuff that we can inherently identify
just through out of the box models
and stuff, where we could use feedback
from the user, uh, to gain even
more context and object awareness.
Anders: And that also
applies landscape level.
Yeah.
Some level of recall.
Yeah, some, which is a
different called yeah.
Vision ai.
Cedric: Yeah.
The other aspect with, with this too,
and this is not a capability that we've
necessarily delivered, but a capability
that we would partner with is the
straight up GIS of like mapping a site.
So in the case of GATX,
there's static features.
We need to be able to draw the tracks.
We need to be able to figure out
exactly what areas we're gonna be flying
over, what the path of the drone is.
But then there's also operations where
we partner with a company like Skyla.
Right?
And that also that involves both.
Like the regulatory, like filing for
the licenses and bringing licensed
pilots to, um, monitor the drone,
which is likely going to be, that's
that partnership or some similar, but
it's, it's part of the full driving
is we need those providers and price.
Okay.
Uh, what about.
Edges are curious.
Is that also part of this?
It, it could be.
I think it applies more and now there's
two different layers of edge, right?
So it applies more to real time
video processing, but now we
can deploy models to drones.
So there's edge on site, edge on drone.
Um, let's see how
Anders: configurable that is, but
Cedric: well, yeah, I mean that's
why we bought the matric for it.
Yeah.
Anders: Okay.
Cedric: Yeah.
Karan: Okay.
Not the specific wording or uh, or
just, just directionally speaking.
Are we good on the stack?
Bottom up and, and the fact that we
are more IP based at the bottom right,
which could be our IP or someone else's
ip in case of drain is not our ip.
And then we, yeah.
And then as we go up, it become,
we become more custom heavy, right?
Because we are very, so solving
a very customer specific
situational problem, right?
The end user experience will
always be different for different
provider, different users.
Of course we can, so does, does, is this
making sense for all of us or, yeah, yeah.
I
Cedric: mean the, the, the bottom two
layers are really for industry provided,
and then when we get to the middle.
That's, that's
Karan: ip.
I, I totally agree with you.
Uh, IP industry provided,
Patrick: yeah.
Karan: Can I just share one thing?
Yes, sir.
Patrick: I'll just share
a screen for a sec.
Cedric: This looks like a wordly, Matt.
Just, uh, you cannot start
Patrick: screen sharing while,
Cedric: yeah,
Patrick: I just, okay.
I'll just be really quick.
Karin, I wanted to share this.
Cedric and I built this back
8 million years ago when we
were trying to get with cn.
Oh yeah.
And so I think what you just
drew is a component sits in,
in a bunch of these parts.
So, because when we tell the story
to the customer, I think we need to
be very thoughtful about this stuff
that happens at the front end, right?
Which is, what are my objectives?
What am I trying to achieve?
Uh, from a business case perspective,
how am I gonna define what I
need from a data perspective?
And how am I, and how am I gonna
ca what am I gonna capture?
And then all that stuff you just drew,
uh, on the whiteboard is the right level
of, is like an expansion of the level
of detail that we have here, right?
So after we showed a customer this story
that says, look, we'll work with you to
do the objectives, we'll work with you
to define the data that you need in order
to do the objectives that you've defined.
And then we're gonna capture some
stuff and we're gonna train the model.
So the dr the picture you drew, if I just
take a, whatever, one of these, like,
it covers basically this stuff here.
Karan: Yeah.
The, the, the way I'm trying to define
you are right Patrick, the way I'm
trying to define that, and maybe this
is the version that, you know, there's
a hybrid version between these two.
What I'm trying to kind of orient
ourselves in, in a mindset is, okay, if
we were to not take cn, not take GATX and
try to solve for a a hundred percent Yeah.
Classical drone based problem,
what would that look like?
Yeah.
And we were to, if we were to
stack these capabilities up.
Where exactly, what's the
continuum of these capabilities?
Right?
Yeah.
Where does it go from, okay, we've
done this, we have packaged this.
We can take it out somewhat
out of the box, and now we can
take that up out of the box.
Just like the CN planning and
scheduling problem, right?
They like the fact that we have a core
defined engine that does planning and
scheduling, but they also like the fact
that we are building solutions around
it that solves for their problem.
So.
So I think we'll talk about the go
to market piece of it, but, but I
just wanna make sure that five of us
have an Oh, a hundred percent equal
understanding of this problem statement.
Right?
Patrick: Yeah, I, I couldn't agree more.
Yeah.
Karan: Excellent.
So, so with that in mind, uh, just
Patrick: lemme bring the whiteboard up.
Uh, and just so you know, Karin,
my, that doc, the diagram I shared
was more of a. Conversation about
the journey we take with the
customer as opposed to the solution.
Yes.
Yes, exactly.
Yeah,
Karan: exactly.
I think it's when we know who the
customer is, we can actually go
more, more specific around it.
Exactly.
Um,
Cedric: I, I sent you a slack with that
wordly map that we drew for, uh, DTY.
There's a, there's a lot of stuff in
there that I think mirrors what we're
looking at here, but it might be an
interesting exercise to go through that.
And just figure out like what, what in
there is custom to GA Ts and what is not?
'cause I think there's really only
two or three things that wouldn't
apply to the layers that you have.
Yeah.
Karan: Okay.
All right.
So asking me, honestly,
Casey: this is replicable.
All of all of it.
Yeah.
Cedric: I mean the only, the only anything
that says rail, you could just like swap
out, you know, the domain or their domain.
Yeah.
Karan: Uh, s you'll have to pull
it up because it's asking, it's
not letting me log into this.
Cedric: Oh, okay.
Let me, let me join the meeting.
Karan: Mm-hmm.
I'm gonna stop the share here.
Cedric: Let me tell you what, let
me pull it up in figure minutes.
I'm sharing one second.
So this, this year.
Um, I imagine some of you remember
this from back in the day.
Karan: I remember it, yeah.
Cedric: Yeah.
So go, go away.
She, wait, I need to look
at my screen 'cause it's on.
Right?
So ignore pub sub.
That stuff doesn't matter anymore.
But you know what, what we're
effectively talking about is drones
themselves are now more mainstream.
Drone docs are not.
So even having expertise around that.
Is useful.
Photogrammetry would be the visualization
thing that we're talking about.
OCR is one aspect of identification.
Yard positioning, um, is,
is geographic, uh, stuff.
Detection is what we were
talking about before.
Um, and then there's all this
other stuff that sits at the bottom
that I think is also helpful.
Knowhow.
So the ability to operationalize a
vision, AI pipeline, the ability to do
monitoring, observability, all that stuff.
Is not a thing within the drone community.
Even building like the infrastructure.
Karan: What's the
representation for the color?
Cedric: What's
Maurice: that?
The colors You
Cedric: say the colors are, oh, sorry.
There's a legend over on the side here.
Okay.
Right.
So like this, this effectively
maps to various skill sets
in the end to end stack.
Um, where that bump?
What's that?
Let me, let me get rid of
the side panel if I can.
And that bump.
Oh yeah, big one is really noisy
about trying to get you to see stuff.
Um, so yeah, like this, this here might
actually be a reasonable exercise to
take what you've had common and just
like map it to something generic.
Karan: Yeah, you have it
almost 90% there, Cedric.
I would just abstract abstracted
out of A-G-A-D-X situation here.
Yeah.
Right.
And this is this.
I, I saw this and I, you know, I,
I remember I was, was blown away
by the way you represented it.
This is weird.
Right.
Maurice: Um, because the only
thing here is that very top layer.
Yeah.
I mean, that just could be domain.
Your domain.
It's
Cedric: basically asset
history, asset search.
Um, let.
Anything that says Railcar could
just be replaced with the word
asset and it'll apply everywhere.
Karan: Yeah.
But what I ask you to think through
is if you abstract it out of GATX and
apply your current thinking on it,
because this is, this is a few months
old and you know, the world has, our
world has changed in those months,
how would these thoughts move, right.
From Genesis to custom to product
and services to commodity?
Right.
So because, because I think
then that, that's where we have
the delineation line, right?
To say, okay, what's in our, you
know, drone suite that's available
that can, that's that the cust the
customer will find valuable regardless.
And what's in our, what's, what
can we add as a layer on top from
a customer and genesis standpoint
that really drives value out of it?
Because I think hundred my.
My going in thesis here is
doing it a hundred percent.
Professional services is, it
means we've done something wrong.
Cedric: Right, right.
So, well, and everything is really,
like, everything really here, like
let's say to here is something
that we can make a platform.
Anders: Yeah.
So Ron is, is there any industry
verticals we're looking at specifically?
Or is this, are we gonna make
it as generic as possible?
Karan: Think about the world
where it makes sense, right?
We have only finite number of in
industries that will be interested in
our drone based operation, where they
are asset heavy and asset intensive.
Yeah, the, the, the, the geographical
reach is large enough for people
not, not making sense for people
to go figure out what's where.
Um, so in that sense, you are looking
at, you're looking at agriculture,
you are looking at transportation,
you are looking at utilities.
You're looking at oil and gas and energy.
Um, so one, one, the company.
Yeah.
Casey: Uh,
Anders: sky Letter was talking with,
and, and, you know, have, as a customer
is one of the big container ports Yes.
I think on Coast.
And it's like there's a lot of assets
there and they're very similar.
So how do, how do they even
keep an overview of that?
They have a lot of methods obviously,
and I think they're very good at it.
Same way you would look at GHX, of
course they have their processes and
of course they're very good at it.
But is there room for improvement?
Cedric: Yeah.
Perfect.
So they already
Anders: have drones flying.
That's even better for us because now
we just get to actually, you know,
enable some of all that they get.
Bless you, Patrick.
Karan: That
Anders: was
Karan: quite, didn't get time to mute
Microsecond, uh.
Cedric: Yeah, I mean, I think
it's actually, it would be a
useful thing to start to interview
some direct representatives from
these industries because shipping
containers, uh, in ports, for example,
I, I know that they use drones.
But they are likely manually
piloting those drones.
Yes.
So there's, and and I think that that
will not change in many circumstances.
Like you will still be
manually piloting the drone.
It's what, what intelligence
can you extract as Yes.
Being, so now that you
Anders: actually get that feed, are you
using that data for anything downstream?
Yeah.
And I think that's,
that's what's interesting.
Maurice: Yeah.
I'd, I'd be curious though, also what.
What methods, let's say a rail yard
is using for managing locations.
Like, are they using RFID or like,
you know, yeah, there's, you know,
'cause I know you talked with
multilayered, um, location validation.
Patrick: Go ahead.
Yeah, I was just gonna throw something
in, um, Cedric, your point about.
The being at a, uh, what did you say, A
shipyard or a dockyard, whatever it is.
Yeah.
Uh, port shipping.
Port, uh, yeah, sorry.
Mentally slowing down.
Um, I, I was gonna say that, um, you said
manually operating the drone, so that's
the first layer, but the second layer is.
It's like somebody sitting there looking
at what the drone's looking at and
making decisions about what they see.
What we're trying to do is take
that human interpretation part out
and make that totally automated.
Cedric: So I, I think there's an
important, uh, sort of distinction
in, in the marketing message there.
Um, I think that we're not trying to
take the human out of the loop always.
We're trying to augment the human.
So this particular certain insights that
are just, you know, 20 years of experience
and situational awareness, um, you know,
the drone is unlikely to say like, oh,
okay, we actually need to fly to this
part of the shipping container, because
they may have someone like in their
ear saying, let go introspective this.
But we're looking just like, just
like chat bt just like anything
else, we're basically, you know.
Converting them from walking to
being able to ride a bicycle.
You're
Anders: layering in information.
You're layering
Cedric: in into their existing Yeah.
It matters how position the product
and it also matters how you market.
'cause the minute that you say
we're replacing humans now we have
a, a very different challenge.
Especially even with GATX, we're dealing
with unions and that sort of thing.
Patrick: Yeah.
I think my point is, I, I, so I agree.
Um, my point is we don't want
to be taking on use cases.
That are ones where it's like Bob
needs to use the drone to inspect
a particular asset because he wants
to see if a particular box is there.
Whatever.
We just gotta be thoughtful about
how we define the use cases so that
when we define them, they are ones
that happen at scale and at speed
and allow for AI interpretation of
those images to To feed a data layer.
Yeah.
We're not trying to take humans
completely out of the process.
We're taking them out of the.
Processes that make sense, where
we can automate decision making.
Cedric: I, I think the other aspect
there is also that we wanna focus on,
uh, you know, things that are repeatable.
Like we were talking before
about the feedback loop, you
know, with GATX, it's one thing.
Yeah, there is, there is actually
kind of an interesting spin on this
that we were talking about with
GATX is you, you fly the area route
every three hours of shift change.
One of the interesting use cases
would be like, oh, fly to this car.
Right?
Yeah.
Like on, move the drone to this
specific location, because I am
curious about something there.
I'm curious about like what the switch,
what, what the locomotive is doing here.
And so there is a way to take
that information, feed it into
situational awareness, use that
to drive human decisions that use
the exact same capture mechanism.
Um, I don't think there's
anyone doing that.
Uh, I I've not heard of a use
case like that where you could
click on a map and say, go.
Karan: Yeah.
Or the example you have, right.
Port company.
I, I can't find my, uh, container.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, drone.
Go
Casey: find it.
Karan: Right?
Yeah.
And, and drone comes back and says, okay,
here's, here's the location of drawing,
you know, of container 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
Yeah.
Cedric: And
Karan: you
Cedric: might know like it's
in this section of the guard
because it hasn't moved.
So it you're basically doing a search.
Anders: Yeah.
So now you're actually
flipping the narrative.
You're using your digital representation
as your remote control Yeah.
For your capture mechanism.
Yeah.
Just it's cool.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Goes both ways.
Cedric: And it, that could be an
important, uh, that could be an important
use case for inspection specifically.
Right, like inspection, generally
you're looking at static
infrastructure or something like that.
But if I say, go look for power lines
that are down and we have an AI model
that can fly the route and identify
those things in real time without
aton of human intervention or direct
piloting, like that's, that's a win.
You can also deploy array of drones.
Like we're talking about flying one drone,
but even with GATX, we're talking about
flying a whole bunch of drones in tandem.
So being able to do a grided
search, uh, would be exceptional.
I mean, that would be,
that would be really,
Karan: we also, we also have to
recognize which ones get easily
consumed by the drone software stack.
Right.
Which one becomes, you know,
native to the drone software.
So, because ultimately you, you
know, the drones gonna, the drone
companies are gonna keep creeping
up the chain, uh, the stack rather.
Uh, and, uh, we saw the drone
company would, would argue that
they do bridge inspection today.
Uh, it's, it's probably not.
Not a completely true statement, but
you know, you can actually go on Sky
Deer today and go to construction
and, and, uh, you know, an inspection
and you can see some videos where
the drone is doing the inspection.
But we know that's not available out
of the box, but we know that the,
the traditional world of technology,
right, this is the stack is gonna get
consumed by the, the core provider.
Uh, you know, in this case,
uh, the drone company.
And we'll have to think about, okay,
what are those overlapping layers that
we can continue to get, get better at,
which will, which they will take time to
get to, uh, or at some point, you know,
some, some drone company ends up, ends
up kind of figuring out a way to get us,
um, get us involved or buying our ip.
Uh, that might just be the exit.
Exit plan for this, but those
just, we just have to be very
mindful of not competing head on
with these drone companies, uh,
but adding so much value that they
can't kind of see it any other way.
Right.
Oh shit.
You guys are doing such unique
stuff that we would rather be
better off working with you than
trying to undermine your technology.
Anders: I, I think that's all fair for
the lower part of your drawing, kran, but
I think the top part is still missing.
I mean, that's still the bespoke,
we stand everything around the
use cases of these drones and the
docks and the automation workflows,
uh, for these industry verticals.
So I think there's still a very,
very compelling case to, yeah, to
hit the ground running for anyone
who wants to enter this space.
And they could do, right.
And
Cedric: the drone companies, I
think it would be a long shot
for them to go all the way up the
stack to driving decision making.
Like they're gonna get better
at capture, they're gonna get
better at media processing.
And, and I think to your point,
maybe the strategy is to find a
way to meet them in the middle.
Yes.
And get as far over here as we
can before they get over here.
Yes.
But yeah, like I could see us
being an acquisition target for.
Hopefully not Scott, but like, it, it
all tell or DJ I or something like that.
Like we start out as partners and
then we find ways to continue vertical
integration to the point where it
just makes sense for this to be a
spinoff, um, you know, go from a joint.
It's a product offering.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Anders: As,
Cedric: yeah.
That has happened in the past.
I mean, it was like flight, like
there's good examples of other third
party solutions like Flight Base and
DroneDeploy that have found a niche
and at least build partnerships.
Um, but they're focused on very
different use cases than than us.
We would be building stuff on
top of their stuff potentially.
Karan: Okay.
Um, what's our, what's our convers next
step with Genack and um, uh, and Skyla?
Anders: So Sky Letter has kind of
hinted at wanting to introduce us to
that Edge company who is also, you
know, has a portfolio of all kinds of
industry people who are interested in
that and they need a, I don't know,
he's talking on their behalf, but, but
they, they probably look to someone
like us as their software partner.
So let's, let's get that introduction.
Uh, for sure.
That's
Skyla.
Okay.
Anders: Um, yeah, I don't know.
I don't know.
Genack, I don't know.
There's much,
Cedric: genack is sort of expressed
more of an unstructured demand,
um, in that they have a lot of
customers that are using drones and
have sort of latent software needs.
So it's not necessarily an active
need, but like they don't have any.
Custom software development partners.
So I think that's a thread that we
should probably just pull on Yeah.
To gain more insights.
And, you know, maybe the goal
for the quarter is just to get on
a couple of ca calls with their
customers directly to learn.
Um, you know, maybe it starts as
an interview with Nate, you know,
our, our main contact over there.
And then we can sort of see how the
structure of those offerings afterwards
Anders: and the third.
Uh, channel we have is DGI, but that's,
that's pretty closed off at the moment.
I mean, they're obviously
busy with other stuff.
I don't, I mean, you can try to kind
of reignite that conversation, but it's
Cedric: Yeah,
Anders: I think, yeah, I mean, in
a way, but that is a third channel
on the, on the radar, I guess.
Cedric: And their hand in some respects
seems to be forced to pull out of
the US market, but at the same time.
They may pull sort of like a, a composite
TikTok of like, okay, well we still
want to be in the market, but we're
gonna need to find a US manufacturer.
We're gonna need to find
a US software partner.
We're basically going to recreate
the ecosystem that we have
globally within the United States.
And at that point, you know, there is
a lot of opportunity for us to play.
I don't think their hardware is ever
gonna fully pull outta the market.
They just need to change
how it's manufactured.
Anders: And honestly if they're, if
they're more expensive at that point than
they are now, they're still competitive.
Just 'cause of
Cedric: They're yeah, like scottio,
Anders: they're better.
The cost.
Yeah.
Okay.
But again, that's speculation.
It's just, it's, we're, we're
hitting like a brick wall there
when we're trying to reach out to
DGI, so I, they're obviously busy,
Karan: so can we, can we do the following?
Can we.
Honors you take the action to connect
with Sky, to get Skylab connected
us to that edge compute company.
Yeah.
And then let's also talk
to Gen's, CEO or whoever.
It seems like it's a fairly small
company, so we should have access there.
Um, and, and tell your contact
agenda back that listen.
We'd love to figure out a way
that we, we do more of this stuff.
Uh, and you know, is there a way
we can actually talk to, talk
to your, your exec executives?
Because I think that that will also
serve as an insight on where the
drones are being deployed, right?
What, what kind of scenarios
are they looking at?
What kind of industries
are most interesting?
So that probably give us some, some
research insights into, well, who are
these doctors and how that's playing out.
And then DJI, let's just throw a Hail
Mary at DJI see if they have enough time.
Uh, well,
Cedric: fine tel there's, there's
like sort of runner up vendors that
we may have more at traction with.
Tel it would be the error
apparent for the DJI, uh, market.
If DJI has to pull off out
entirely, it's actually not.
I don't think it's, we
Anders: could be curious.
We don't know much, to be honest.
Right.
Cedric: Scottio doesn't have
their own flight, or, sorry.
Um, uh, Tel doesn't have their own flight
hub, but they do have a DOC solution.
Okay.
Yeah, I mean they, they're, it's
Anders: just very manual then.
Okay.
Cedric: Yeah.
They'll, they'll partner with
flight base or something like that.
One note about Genpact is that drones are.
Actually a very small
component of their operations.
They're actually a utility supply
company, so they service all sorts
of things as it relates to electrical
power line inspection, like drones was
actually, actually something that just
spawned out the fact that they were doing
all these things that required drones
and so their drone practices I think
might just be Nate and a couple folks.
Um,
Karan: that's fine.
We'll figure that out.
Probably even better in that case.
Cedric: They have industry, uh,
access that's, that aren't even
using drones yet, so they may be
able to make some introductions
where we can convert together.
Karan: Okay.
Hey, Casey.
Cedric: Oh, hey.
How's it going, man?
Casey: Hey, sorry I missed the,
uh, uh, meeting invite earlier.
Karan: No, no, no, no.
No problem at all.
Um.
So just to kind of catch you up, we
were just talk thinking about, okay,
what, what does the world of drones and
drone based solution looks like for us?
And we just wanted to start this
initial discussion on, okay, if
we have to do this the right way,
what are the components involved?
How does this flow from bottom to the top?
Uh, and, and how do we kind of start
to have conversations with customers?
I think the part that we haven't talked
about is really the content piece, uh,
yet, uh, which I, which I'm hoping we'll
talk with Laura next week, uh, as well.
Um, but the whole idea is, okay, we, we
recognize and kind of connecting this to
the world map that Cedric was showing.
When you join, these are the
pieces we wanna put together
to, to kind of get ourselves.
Recognize as a player, get our message out
there and talk to more and more customer.
Um, so, so that was really kind of the
backdrop of this conversation, uh, so far.
All right, so I, I. You'll be coming
to San Francisco next week, right?
Cedric: Yeah.
I need to book my tickets.
Are we, I'll, I'll follow up, but
I'm curious if we're all staying
at the same hotel or something.
Karan: Uh, no.
The invite just, we, I, I just
sent out the invite this morning,
so I haven't even booked anything.
Um, so yeah, I was
Cedric: asking Patrick about
it, but I, I realized that
the invite just went out, so,
Patrick: yeah.
So I'm flying Monday during the
day and I fly, I have to leave
Thursday morning first thing 'cause
I'm away on the weekend on Friday.
So, um, and I'm staying at the Westin,
which is apparently a mile from the
Cedric: Market Street.
Karan: We might have, we might have
to change our location guys because,
uh, Laura has some mobility issues.
So she requested we moved,
uh, the location within the
city to some other location.
Um, oh, okay.
So I'll, I'll, I'll add it to the invite
once, uh, once we have that locked in.
Cedric: Okay.
Mobility being like aada a mobility
or like can't get to a location?
I,
Karan: I did not.
Cedric: I did not.
Karan: So, um, so we'll, we'll be there
probably in the Pacific Heights area.
Oh, okay.
Cool.
So, not too far.
Um, so let this, let this
percolate, let let this discussion
percolate amongst all of us.
Um, Cedric, is there a way we can use
your Figma board as kind of the, this,
the content of this conversation, or
do you wanna build something new or
something else so that we can just,
Cedric: I can, I can copy it.
It is really just a license thing.
We, we, uh, pay.
Um, let's use,
Karan: let's use notion then.
Cedric: Yeah.
Yeah.
Um, okay.
I'll figure out if there's a way to give
back the guest access, but if not Yeah.
We can use notion.
Karan: Yeah.
Just copy paste the
Anders: channel and a
Notion Channel and yeah.
Get everything consolidated.
Cedric: Yeah, that
Anders: works.
Works.
Cedric: All right.
I'm also to write up a little bit
more of a. Business plan structure
on this, just to put some thoughts
down on market and competition and,
uh, you know, opportunity, regulatory
risk, like that sort of stuff.
Um, so I might have that by
the time we meet next week.
Karan: Yeah, let's do that.
I think the only action, right, right,
we, we have right now is, uh, is just
meeting up with Skyla and Pac and DJI,
uh, let's, let's do our ecosystem.
Outreach and research, see what they have
to say and then, um, and that that'll help
us kind of focus on our message as well.
And then we'll spend a fair bit of
time next week just, just making sure
we get into more details and, and
what, what really needs to be done
technically, right, development wise.
And then, and then of course,
messaging wise, uh, for us to
start to bring the foundation.
Cedric: All good talk.
Cheers.
Thank you guys.
Bye.